Guide to the Lee Snider Photograph Collection ca. 1977-2009 MSS.248
Fales Library and Special Collections
Lee Snider Photograph Collection
1977-2009
Fales Library and Special Collections
Snider, Lee
MSS.248
1.25 Linear Feet in 5 binders, and 1 half manuscript box
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open to researchers. Please contact the Fales Library and Special Collections, fales.library@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596.
Scope and Content note
The Lee Snider Photograph Collection is comprised of black and white prints, color slides, and photo cds documenting AIDS activism and Gay Pride, primarily in New York City, from 1977 through 2009.
Arrangement note
Each Series is arranged chronologically by event, when possible, based on information provided by the creator. Each event is separated by a piece of paper stating a brief description of the event and its date. Unspecified events are filed chronologically by their date. In the instance that only a general date is provided, the event is filed at the end of that time period. All undated and unidentified pieces are located in an "unidentified" file at the end of the series.
Missing Title
Series I: Black and White Prints
Series II: Color Slides
Series III: Photo CDs
Biographical / Historical
Lee Snider has been a successful professional photographer for four decades. His work has appeared in major magazines, newspapers, and in countless books, calendars, and other forms of editorial media.
Lee's work is represented by a number of top stock photography agencies including Getty, Shutterstock, Dreamstime, The Image Works, Deposit Photos, Alamy, and Corbis. He has an extensive library of images from Asia, especially China and Thailand, Canada, Europe, and the USA and specializes in travel photography. His business associate and partner is Xu Lei, originally from Sichuan Province, China.
Included in Lee's photo journalism coverage are images from many seminal events in the New York City LGBT community's history starting in 1977 when he first commenced his career as a photographer.
Gay men -- United States.; Gay activists -- New York (State) -- New York.; AIDS activists -- New York (State) -- New York; Photograph Disks.; Slides (photographs); Black-and-white photographs.; Color slides.; New York (N.Y.).; Photographs.; Lesbians -- United States; Photographers -- United States.; Gays in popular culture.; Activism (LGBTQ); Photography |z United States.; Paris (France); Washington (D.C.); United States |x Armed Forces |x Gays.; ACT UP (Organization); Queer Nation (Organization); Redgrave, Lynn, 1943-; Appuzo, Virginia; Callan, Michael; Crisp, Quentin; Allen, Peter L., 1957-; Daly, Tyne; Kramer, Larry; Cathedral Project (organization); White, Edmund, 1940-; Duane, Thomas K., 1955-; Horne, Marilyn; Fierstein, Harvey, 1954-; Earle, Brent Nicholson; Hunter, Joyce; AIDS Walk; Randall, Tony
- Series I: Black and White Prints, 1977-1994
  - Hudson River "Gay Piers", 1977, April 1977 (Box 1)
    General
    1 page black and white photographs
  - Everard Baths on 28th Street, NYC, after May 22 fire, May 1977 (Box 1)
  - "Main Man" sign, January 1978 (Box 1)
  - Hudson River "Gay Piers", 1978, June 1978 (Box 1)
    2 pages black and white photographs
  - "Cheap" billboard at Christopher Street and Seventh Avenue, March 1979 (Box 1)
  - Hudson River "Gay Piers", 1980, May 1980 (Box 1)
  - Edmund White, 1980 (Box 1)
    3 pages black and white photographs
  - Gay area of Les Tuilleries / Seine River Quay, Paris, France 1981 (Box 1)
  - Gay Expo at a Hudson Street school, 1982 (Box 1)
  - Hudson River "Gay Piers", 1983, June 1983 (Box 1)
    1 page black and white phtotgraphs
  - First AIDS memorial service in New York City, Central Park bandshell, June 1983, June 13, 1983 (Box 1)
    4 pages black and white photographs
  - Ass Trick, Village gay bar, NYC, 1983 (Box 1)
  - The New St. Marks baths, The Anvil self-induced closure, J's, the Mineshaft closure, the Adonis Theater marquee, the Show Palace Theatre marquee, Eros theater marquee, November 1985 (Box 1)
    10 pages black and white photographs
  - Demonstration at City Hall, November, 1985, November 15, 1985 (Box 1)
    16 pages black and white photographs
  - GLADL Rally at NY Post, December, 1985, December 1, 1985 (Box 1)
    5 pages black and white photographs
  - The Adonis Theater marquee, the Show Palace Theatre marquee, March 1986 (Box 1)
  - Waiting at City Hall during the Gay Rights Bill Hearing, March 1986, March 11, 1986 (Box 1)
  - Rally Supporting the Gay Rights Bills, March 1986, March 18, 1986 (Box 1)
    6 pages black and white photographs
  - Waiting at City Hall for the Results of the Gay Rights Bill Vote, March 1986, March 20, 1986 (Box 1)
    9 pages black and white photographs
  - Protest at the National Review, April 1986, April 30, 1986 (Box 1)
  - AIDS Walk 1986; Virginia Apuzzo, Peter Allen (Box 1)
  - Rally Opposing Supreme Court Justice Warren Burger, August 1986, August 11, 1986 (Box 2)
    13 pages black and white photographs
  - Opening Ceremonies of the Liberty Games Gay Softball Tournament, August 1986, August 24, 1986 (Box 2)
  - Joyce Hunter, 1986 (Box 2)
  - The Adonis Theater, 1986 (Box 2)
  - Everard Spa closure, 1986 (Box 2)
  - Demonstration on Wall Street, March 1987, March 3, 1987 (Box 2)
  - AIDS Walk 1987; Joel Grey, Lynn Redgrave, May 1987 (Box 2)
  - Brent Nicholson Earle, undated (Box 2)
  - Demonstration at St. Patrick's Cathedral, March 1988, March 6, 1988 (Box 2)
  - ACT UP Demonstration on Wall Street, March 1988, March 24, 1988 (Box 2)
  - St. Patrick's Cathedral, Easter 1988, April 3, 1988 (Box 2)
  - Cathedral Project, May 1988, May 1, 1988 (Box 2)
  - ACT UP Rally at City Hall Park, May 1988, May 2, 1988 (Box 2)
  - ACT UP Demonstration in Harlem, May 1988, May 3, 1988 (Box 2)
  - ACT UP Demonstration at the International Building, May 1988, May 5, 1988 (Box 2)
  - ACTUP Demonstration at the Plaza Hotel, May 1988, May 6, 1988 (Box 2)
  - Cathedral Project, August 1988, August 7, 1988 (Box 2)
  - St. Patrick's Cathedral, October 1988, October 2, 1988 (Box 2)
  - Cathedral Project, November 1988, November 6, 1988 (Box 3)
  - Press conference, Mayor Ed Koch, 1988 (Box 3)
  - PWA Health Group Conference, March 1989, March 6, 1989 (Box 3)
    7 pages black and white photographs
  - ACT UP Demonstration at Brooklyn Bridge/City Hall, March 1989, March 28, 1989 (Box 3)
  - Demonstration at COSMO Awards Ceremony, April 1989, April 26, 1989 (Box 3)
  - ACT UP Demonstration at Housing Resources Administration-NYC, September 1989, September 5, 1989 (Box 3)
  - ACT UP Demonstration at the New York Stock Exchange, September 1989, September 14, 1989 (Box 3)
    11 pages black and white photographs
  - The Cathedral Project parade at St. Patrick's Cathedral, October 1989, October 30, 1989 (Box 3)
  - ACT UP Demonstration at Trump Tower, NYC, October 1989, October 31, 1989 (Box 3)
  - ACT UP Demonstration at St. Patrick's Cathedral, December 1989, December 10, 1989 (Box 3)
  - Queer Nation demonstration, June 1990, June 23, 1990 (Box 3)
  - Protest at Channel 13/WNET-TV, November 1990 (Box 3)
  - ACT UP Protest at St. Patrick's Cathedral, December 1990, December 9, 1990 (Box 3)
  - "Lift the Ban" against gays in the military rally, 1991 (Box 4)
  - AIDS Walk 1991; Tyne Daly, Marilyn Horne (Box 4)
  - GLAAD/Queer Nation Demonstration Against Carter-Wallace, November 1991, November 7, 1991 (Box 4)
  - GMHC: "Ten Days, Ten Deeds," November 1991, November 25, 1991 (Box 4)
  - GMHC: "Ten Days, Ten Deeds," November, 1991, November 26, 1991 (Box 4)
    4 pages black and whote photographs
  - ILGO Members in the St. Patrick's Day Parade, March 1992, March 17, 1992 (Box 4)
  - ACT UP Members in the "United for AIDS Action" Demonstration, July 1992, July 14, 1992 (Box 4)
    12 pages black and white photographs
  - George Segal's "Gay Liberation" scultpure after installation, NYC, 1992 (Box 4)
  - AIDS Walk 1993; Tony Randall (Box 4)
  - AIDS Walk 1994; Joan Rivers, Mayor Rudolph Giuliani, Jeff Richardson, Jon Stewart, cast of Broadway's "Carousel" (Box 4)
  - Quentin Crisp, undated (Box 4)
  - Harvey Fierstein, undated (Box 4)
  - Demonstration in front of NY Telephone, NYC, undated (Box 4)
  - Unidentified, undated (Box 4)
- Series II: Color Slides, 1986-2004
  - NYC: AIDS Walk 1986, May 18, 1986 (Box 5)
    1 page, 8 color slides
  - NYC: AIDS Walk 1987, May 17, 1987 (Box 5)
  - March on Washington, DC, October 1987, October 10-11, 1987 (Box 5)
    1 page, 17 color slides
  - AIDS Quilt: NYC Pier 92, June 1988, June 21, 1988 (Box 5)
    1 page, 14 color slides
  - AIDS Quilt: NYC's Central Park, June 1988, June 25, 1988 (Box 5)
    1 page, 12 color slides
  - NYC: Gay Pride March, June 1990 (Box 5)
    1 page, 20 color slides
  - NYC: AIDS Walk, May 1990, May 20, 1990 (Box 5)
    1 page, 6 color slides
  - NYC: AIDS Walk, May 1991 (Box 5)
  - NYC: AIDS Walk, May 1993, May 2, 1993 (Box 5)
  - NYC: AIDS Walk, 1994 (Box 5)
    2 pages, 31 color slides
  - Stonewall 25 March: NYC, June 1994, June 26, 1994 (Box 5)
    1 page, 13 color slides
  - Names Project AIDS Quilt: Washington, DC, December 1996, December 12, 1996 (Box 5)
  - NYC: Gay Pride Parade, June 2002, June 30, 2002 (Box 5)
    4 pages, 78 color slides
  - NYC: Gay Pride, June 2004, June 27, 2004 (Box 5)
    5 pages, 86 color slides
- Series III: Photo CDs, 2005-2009
  - NYC: Gay Pride 2005, June 2005 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    252 photos
  - NYC: Gay Pride Parade 2008, June 29, 2008 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    160 photos
  - NYC: Gay Pride Parade 2009, June 28, 2009 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    282 photos